{  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Forms of worldview include:",
      "options": [
        "Consciousness, thinking, mind",
        "Myth, religion, philosophy",
        "God, nature, society",
        "Ontology, epistemology, axiology",
        "Man, person, individual"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Philosophical direction recognizing one beginning of the world:",
      "options": ["Dualism", "Agnosticism", "Mechanism", "Monism", "Pluralism"],
      "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Philosophical doctrine that denies the fundamental possibility of knowing the world:",
      "options": [
        "Skepticism",
        "Agnosticism",
        "Sensationalism",
        "Anthropologism",
        "Atheism"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "The meaning of the term Philosophy:",
      "options": [
        "Love of wisdom",
        "Love of Idea",
        "Love of thinking",
        "Love of Science",
        "Love of Truth"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "The first form of worldview:",
      "options": ["Religion", "Mythology", "Philosophy", "Art", "Morality"],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Teachings about Being:",
      "options": [
        "Epistemology",
        "Axiology",
        "Anthology",
        "Anthropology",
        "Ontology"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 4
    },
    {
      "question": "Philosophical direction stating “Space and time are forms of our perception” belongs to:",
      "options": [
        "Materialism",
        "Objective idealism",
        "Subjective idealism",
        "Dialectical materialism",
        "Mechanistic materialism"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Two main sides of the main question of philosophy:",
      "options": [
        "Sophistry, eclecticism, dogmatism",
        "Monism, dualism, pluralism",
        "Sociology, political science, cultural studies",
        "Ontology, Gnoseology",
        "Mythology, religion, philosophy"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "Teaching about knowledge:",
      "options": [
        "Ontology",
        "Gnoseology",
        "Metaphysics",
        "Axiology",
        "Anthropology"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Recognition of two substances at the foundation of being:",
      "options": [
        "Pluralism",
        "Dualism",
        "Monism",
        "Conventionalism",
        "Parallelism"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "Socrates' method, which helps to give birth to new knowledge, is called:",
      "options": [
        "Maieutics",
        "Dialectics",
        "Hermeneutics",
        "Eclectic",
        "Sophistry"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "The main task of philosophy is the construction of a new method of science, believed:",
      "options": [
        "Socrates",
        "Rene Descartes",
        "Francis Bacon",
        "Georg Hegel",
        "Aristotle"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "The philosopher who formulated 4 methodological rules:",
      "options": [
        "Socrates",
        "Rene Descartes",
        "Francis Bacon",
        "Georg Hegel",
        "Aristotle"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "He created a philosophical system based on the dialectical method:",
      "options": [
        "Socrates",
        "Rene Descartes",
        "Francis Bacon",
        "Georg Hegel",
        "Aristotle"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "A philosophical method based on the principles of interpretation of any texts or systems of concepts:",
      "options": [
        "Maieutics",
        "Dialectics",
        "Hermeneutics",
        "Eclectic",
        "Sophistry"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "This function is that philosophy develops the basic methods of cognition of the reality:",
      "options": [
        "The worldview function",
        "The methodological function",
        "The moral function",
        "The axiological function",
        "The motivational function"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "This function of philosophy is to develop a worldview position:",
      "options": [
        "The worldview function",
        "The methodological function",
        "The moral function",
        "The axiological function",
        "The motivational function"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "This function of philosophy asserts the consciously normative attitude of a person to himself and to other people:",
      "options": [
        "The worldview function",
        "The methodological function",
        "The moral function",
        "The axiological function",
        "The motivational function"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "This function of philosophy teaches us to recognize the values of the surrounding world:",
      "options": [
        "The worldview function",
        "The methodological function",
        "The moral function",
        "The axiological function",
        "The motivational function"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "This function of philosophy brings up certain interests and ideals in a person, which determine the motives of his behavior and the achievement of his goals:",
      "options": [
        "The worldview function",
        "The methodological function",
        "The moral function",
        "The axiological function",
        "The motivational function"
      ],
      "correct_answer": 4
    }
  ]
}
